Linda Pershing "Ribbon around the Pentagon" collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Linda Pershing "Ribbon around the Pentagon" collection 1984-2018 1985-1989
AFC 2018/007
Pershing, Linda
approximately 1,606 items
8 containers
4 linear feet
approximately 288 pages
5 photographic prints: black-and-white; 4 x 5 in., 5 x 7 in.
131 photographic prints: color; 3 1/2 x 5 in.
971 photographic transparencies: color; 35mm
4 photographic transparencies: color; 4 x 5 1/2 in.
1 photographic negative: black-and-white; 4 x 5 in.
102 photographic negatives: color; 35mm
4 videocassettes (VHS): analog
50 audiocassettes: analog
30 microcassettes: analog
9 fabric panels: approximately 17 x 45 in.
1 cleaning microcassette
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection of ethnographic research data about Justine Merritt's "Ribbon around the Pentagon" project and subsequent related events. Includes several original Ribbon panels, audio interviews with participants, photographs of various Ribbon project events, video of lectures and documentaries, questionnaire responses, and signed copies of publications written by the collector.
Provenance
Linda Pershing; Donation; 2018.
Custodial History
All Ribbon panels, many photographs, and some documents in the collection were created by Ribbon project panel makers, primarily in the United States, between 1984 and 1989. Linda Pershing began collecting these materials from panel makers and Ribbon project founding officers in 1985 or 1986, and they remained in her possession until their donation to the American Folklife Center in 2018. Linda Pershing created all audio recordings, some photographs, and some documents, which remained in her possession until their donation in 2018.
Accruals
Additional Ribbon panels may be accrued in the future.
Related Material
The Ribbon Records (Mss 043), Texas Woman's University
Access and Restrictions
The Linda Pershing "Ribbon around the Pentagon" collection is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Linda Pershing is a folklorist with a focus on women's experiences and feminist theory, peace and justice activism, feminist pedagogy, folklore studies, and the politics of culture.
For six years following the "Ribbon around the Pentagon" event which took place in the summer of 1985, Pershing traveled around the country to interview Ribbon project participants at their homes, photograph Ribbon panels, and collect qualitative research data about the project. She wrote about her ethnographic research of the Ribbon project in her essay Peace Work out of Piecework: Feminist Needlework Metaphors and the Ribbon around the Pentagon (1993) and in her books Sew to Speak: The Fabric Art of Mary Milne (1995) and The Ribbon around the Pentagon: Peace by Piecemakers (1996).
Scope and Content
The "Ribbon around the Pentagon" ceremony was a grass-roots public art event and anti-nuclear peace demonstration which took place in Washington, D.C., on August 4, 1985 (the weekend before the 40th anniversary of the atomic bombing of Hiroshima, Japan). Activists protesting nuclear arms created hand-made fabric panels which depicted the things that would be lost in the event of a nuclear disaster. Panels showcased a variety of fiber arts including embroidery, quilting, garment sewing, fabric painting, knitting, weaving, appliqué, and needlework. The panels were tied together to form a 15-mile long "Ribbon," and the Ribbon was wrapped around the Pentagon, the Capitol, and the Lincoln and Washington Memorials by demonstrators holding the panels they created.
The collection primarily consists of the opinions of participants and the imagery of Ribbon panels. Collection materials include several original Ribbon panels, photographs of Ribbon panels, photographs of events which took place after the original 1985 demonstration, video of lectures and documentaries, audio interviews with project founders and participants, and questionnaire responses. All Ribbon panels, most documents, and many photographs in the collection were created by Ribbon project participants, primarily in the United States, between 1984 and 1989. All audio recordings and many photographs were created by Linda Pershing between 1985 and 1989.
The materials in this collection refer to the original ceremony and related activities which took place from 1984 to 1989 as "the Ribbon project."
Arrangement
The Linda Pershing "Ribbon around the Pentagon" collection is organized into five series:
Series 1: Justine Merritt
Series 2: Mary Milne
Series 3: Other Ribbon project participants
Series 4: Research materials
Series 5: Donation notes
Two subjects stand out due to the depth of documentation and their prominence in Linda Pershing's publications: Ribbon project founder Justine Merritt; and project participant Mary Milne. Most materials related to these subjects have been arranged in distinct groupings for ease of reference.
Photographs are listed with the date they were taken; when that is unknown, the photograph development or copy date is listed.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Hollis, Susan T., Feminist theory and the study of folklore. 1993.; Merritt, Justine, 1924-2009--Interviews.; Merritt, Justine, 1924-2009. Cup of cool water.; Milne, Mary, 1955- --Interviews.; Pershing, Linda; Pershing, Linda. Sew to speak. 1995.
Subjects
Antinuclear movement--United States--20th century.; Catholic women artists--United States--Interviews.; Craftivism--United States.; Fabric pictures--United States.; Folk art.; Material culture.; Needlework--Social aspects.; Nuclear disarmament--United States--20th century.; Textile artists--United States--Interviews.; Textile crafts--Political aspects--United States.; Women and peace--United States.
Places
Washington (D.C.)
Form/Genre
Interviews.; Manuscripts.; Oral histories.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.
Container List
- Series 1: Justine Merritt, 1984-1989
  Taped interviews and lectures, photos, an original textile Ribbon panel, and a documentary video about Justine Merritt, the founder of the Ribbon project. Much of Linda Pershing's book The Ribbon around the Pentagon: Peace by Piecemakers (1996) focused on Justine Merritt and included references to the materials in this series. The series combines tapes recorded by Linda Pershing with photos and videos she collected from other sources. The Ribbon panel is an original work created by Justine Merritt.
  - Justine Merritt interviews
    - Justine Merritt interview, St. John's University, Collegeville, MN, April 25, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR015; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt interview, Denton, TX (1 of 3), April 26, 1987, AFC 2018/007: SR016; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt interview, Denton, TX (2 of 3), April 26, 1987, AFC 2018/007: SR017; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt interview, Denton, TX (3 of 3), April 26, 1987, AFC 2018/007: SR018; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt interview, Austin, TX, April 27, 1987, AFC 2018/007: SR019; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt interview, June Thompson's house, Redwood City, CA, June 6, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR020; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt interview, Linda Pershing's house, Austin, TX (1 of 6), April 18 to 19, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR021; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt interview, Linda Pershing's house, Austin, TX (2 of 6), April 18 to 19, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR022; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt interview, Linda Pershing's house, Austin, TX (3 of 6), April 18 to 19, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR023; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Side A of SR023. See also Side B.
    - Justine Merritt interview, Linda Pershing's house, Austin, TX (4 of 6), April 18 to 19, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR024; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt interview, Linda Pershing's house, Austin, TX (5 of 6), April 18 to 19, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR025; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Side B of SR025. See also Side A.
    - Justine Merritt interview, Linda Pershing's house, Austin, TX (6 of 6), April 18 to 19, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR026; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
  - Ribbon panels by Justine Merritt
    - Ribbon panel, "Names," circa 1985, AFC 2018/007: AR001; 1 textile (17 3/4 x 33 1/2 in.; embroidery); Made by Justine Merritt (Box 8)
      Linda Pershing's description: "Fourth 'names' panel with names of people she would hate to lose in a nuclear war, embroidered. Many were people she met as she traveled the U.S. promoting the project. Justine said that she left the bottom empty to symbolize the people who would come into her life in the future. See p. 90 in Pershing's book."
    - Photo of Justine Merritt holding one of her "names" panels, circa 1984 to 1989, 1 black-and-white negative (4 x 5 in.); 1 black-and-white photographic print (5 x 7 in.) (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Photos of Justine Merritt's "map" Ribbon panel, developed May 1987, AFC 2018/007: PH001; 5 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 2)
    - Photos of Justine Merritt and others viewing Justine's "names" panel at Linda Pershing's house in Austin, TX, circa April 18 to 19, 1989, AFC 2018/007: PH002; 37 color transparencies (35mm slides); Photographs attributed to Linda Pershing (Box 2)
  - Justine Merritt lectures
    - Justine Merritt lecture, St. John's University, Collegeville, MN, April 24, 1986, AFC 2018/007: MV002; 1 videocassette (120 min.); Recording attributed to Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt lecture, St. John's University, Collegeville, MN, April 24, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR001; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt presentation, St. John's University, Collegeville, MN (1 of 2), April 25, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR002; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt presentation, St. John's University, Collegeville, MN (2 of 2), April 25, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR003; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Photos of Justine Merritt lecturing with panels, developed May 1986, AFC 2018/007: PH003; 5 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 2)
    - Justine Merritt presentation, Ribbon party at Linda Pershing's house, Austin, TX (1 of 2), July 29, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR004; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt presentation, Ribbon party at Linda Pershing's house, Austin, TX (2 of 2), July 29, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR005; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt presentation, meeting of the Austin Stitchery Guild, Austin, TX, January 29, 1987, AFC 2018/007: SR006; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt lecture, Texas Woman's University, Denton, TX, April 27, 1987, AFC 2018/007: MV003; 1 videocassette (120 min.); Recording attributed to Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt lecture, St. John's University, Collegeville, MN, April 26 to 27, 1987, AFC 2018/007: SR007; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt presentation, Denton, TX (1 of 4), April 27, 1987, AFC 2018/007: SR008; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt presentation, Denton, TX (2 of 4), April 27, 1987, AFC 2018/007: SR009; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt presentation, Denton, TX (3 of 4), April 27, 1987, AFC 2018/007: SR010; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Justine Merritt presentation, Denton, TX (4 of 4), April 27, 1987, AFC 2018/007: SR011; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Photos of Justine Merritt lecturing with panels, developed circa May 1987, 7 color photographic prints (3 1/2 x 5 in.) (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Photos of Justine Merritt lecturing with panels, developed May 1987, AFC 2018/007: PH004; 2 color transparencies (35mm slides) (Box 2)
    - Justine Merritt lecture, St. Edward's University, Austin, TX, April 19, 1989, AFC 2018/007: MV004; 1 videocassette (120 min.); Recording attributed to Linda Pershing; First recording on MV004. See also second and third recordings.
    - Justine Merritt lecture, St. Edward's University, Austin, TX, April 19, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR025; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Side A of SR025. See also Side B.
    - Justine Merritt presentation, Austin Women's Peace House, Austin, TX, April 19, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR012; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
  - Audio program featuring Justine Merritt
    - A Cup of Cool Water: Meditations on the Life of Christ (1 of 2), n.d., AFC 2018/007: SR013; 1 audiocassette; Presented by Justine Merritt,; © Creative Core
    - A Cup of Cool Water: Meditations on the Life of Christ (2 of 2), n.d., AFC 2018/007: SR014; 1 audiocassette; Presented by Justine Merritt,; © Creative Core
- Series 2: Mary Milne, 1987-1990
  Taped interviews, photos, and a documentary video about Mary Milne, a prolific participant of the Ribbon project and the subject of Linda Pershing's book Sew to Speak: The Fabric Art of Mary Milne. The series consists primarily of audiotapes and photographs created by Linda Pershing. The video documentary was produced by Mary Milne.
  - Mary Milne interviews
    - Mary Milne interview (standard questions), Ithaca, NY (1 of 3), May 3, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR027; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Mary Milne interview (special questions), Ithaca, NY (2 of 3), May 3, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR028; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Mary Milne interview, Ithaca, NY (3 of 3), May 3, 1989, AFC 2018/007: SR029; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Side A of SR029. See also Side B.
  - Ribbon panels, artworks, studio, and home of Mary Milne
    - Photos of Mary Milne, her daughter, and her artwork, circa 1988 to 1990, AFC 2018/007: PH005; 4 color transparencies (4 x 5 1/2 in.); Photographed by Mary Milne (Box 7)
    - Photos of Mary Milne's panels and 1985 calendar Can't Kill the Spirit, May 3 to May 4, 1989, AFC 2018/007: PH006; 45 color negatives (35mm); 85 color photographic prints (3 1/2 x 5 in.); Photographed by Linda Pershing (Box 7, Box-folder 1/3)
    - Photos of Ribbon panels made by Mary Milne, May 3 to May 4, 1989, 6 color photographic prints (3 1/2 x 5 in.); Photographed by Linda Pershing (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Photos of Mary Milne, her panels, and views of Ithaca, NY, May 3 to May 4, 1989, AFC 2018/007: PH007; 21 color transparencies (35mm slides); Photographed by Linda Pershing (Box 2)
    - Photos of a Ribbon panel by Mary Milne and a view of Ithaca Commons in Ithaca, NY, May 3 to May 4, 1989, AFC 2018/007: PH008; 2 color transparencies (35mm slides); Photographed by Linda Pershing (Box 2)
    - Additional photos of Ribbon panels by Mary Milne and 1985 calendar Can't Kill the Spirit, developed August 1994, AFC 2018/007: PH009; 3 color transparencies (35mm slides); Photographed by Linda Pershing (Box 2)
  - Video program featuring Mary Milne
    - Fabricollage, 1987, AFC 2018/007: MV004; 1 videocassette (120 min.); Produced by Mary Milne; Third recording on MV004. See also first and second recordings.
- Series 3: Other Ribbon project participants, 1984-1989
  Taped interviews, photographs of events, photographs of Ribbon panels, original textile Ribbon panels, documentary videos, study data about the Ribbon project, and photo submissions to a book publisher. This series combines audiotapes recorded by Linda Pershing with photographs, video recordings, study data, and book submissions that she collected from other sources. The materials in this series are referenced throughout Linda Pershing's book, The Ribbon around the Pentagon: Peace by Piecemakers (1996). Most materials about Justine Merritt and Mary Milne have been removed to separate series above for ease of use, except for the Subseries "Ribbon events" which depicts all participants including Merritt and Milne.
  - Ribbon project interviews
    - California
      - Sherry Lowe and Betty Mihalaros interview, Oakland, CA (1 of 2), June 4, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR030; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Sherry Lowe and Betty Mihalaros interview, Oakland, CA (2 of 2), June 4, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR031; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Alexandra Genetti interview, Portola Valley, CA (1 of 2), June 5, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR032; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Alexandra Genetti interview, Portola Valley, CA (2 of 2), June 5 to 6, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR033; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Ed and Miriam Cone interview, Castro Valley, CA, June 6, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR034; 1 audiocassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Kjerstin Walker interview, Berkeley, CA (1 of 2), June 7, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR035; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Side B of SR035. See also Side A.
      - Kjerstin Walker interview, Berkeley, CA (2 of 2), June 7, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR036; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; First recording on Side A of SR036. See also the second recording on Side A, plus all of Side B.
      - Miriam Weber interview, San Francisco, CA, June 7, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR035; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Side A of SR035. See also Side B.
      - Audrey Keller interview, Palo Alto, CA, June 8, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR036; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Second recording on Side A, plus all of Side B, on SR036. See also the first recording on Side A.
      - Ruth Anne "Ra" Black interview, Mountain View, CA, June 7, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR037; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Madeline Mason interview, Oakland, CA, June 8, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR038; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Bill Thompson interview, Redwood City, CA (1 of 2), June 8, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR039; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Bill Thompson interview, Redwood City, CA (2 of 2), June 8, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR040; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Side A of SR040. See also Side B.
      - Jo Imlay interview, San Francisco, CA (1 of 2), June 9, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR040; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Side B of SR040. See also Side A.
      - Jo Imlay interview, San Francisco, CA (2 of 2), June 9, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR041; 1 audiocassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Jo Ann Yates interview, San Francisco, CA, June 9, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR042; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Eileen Drath interview, Portola Valley, CA, June 10, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR043; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - June Thompson interview, Redwood City, CA, June 12, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR044; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - Colorado
      - Mary Jo Peterson interview, Denver, CO (1 of 2), March 22, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR045; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Mary Jo Peterson interview, Denver, CO (2 of 2), March 22, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR046; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Side A of SR046. See also Side B.
      - Ramona Elizalde interview, Denver, CO (1 of 2), March 22, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR046; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Side B of SR046. See also Side A.
      - Ramona Elizalde interview, Denver, CO (2 of 2), March 22, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR047; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Alice Coleman interview, Denver, CO, March 22, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR048; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Lucile Merritt interview, Denver, CO, March 22, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR049; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Side A of SR049. See also Side B.
      - Mary Frances Jaster interview, Denver, CO (1 of 2), March 24, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR050; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Mary Frances Jaster interview, Denver, CO (2 of 2), March 24, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR051; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Pat Hutchinson interview, Denver, CO (1 of 2), March 25, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR049; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Side B of SR049. See also Side A.
      - Pat Hutchinson interview, Denver, CO (2 of 2), March 25, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR052; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Jean Cronin interview, Denver, CO (1 of 2), March 21, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR053; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Jean Cronin interview, Denver, CO (2 of 2), March 21, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR023; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing; Side B of SR023. See also Side A.
      - Photos of Trish Jacket, Jackie Gallero, Elizabeth and Bernie Mantey, Liva Pacheco, Debbie Wilmer, and Adela Quintana, and views of Ignacio, CO, November 11 to 15, 1988, AFC 2018/007: PH010; 23 color transparencies (35mm slides); Photographs attributed to Linda Pershing (Box 2)
      - Trish Jacket interview, Ignacio, CO (1 of 2), November 11, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR054; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Trish Jacket interview, Ignacio, CO (2 of 2), November 11, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR055; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Jackie Gallero interview, Ignacio, CO, November 11, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR056; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Bernie Mantey interview, Ignacio, CO, November 11, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR057; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Elizabeth Mantey interview, Ignacio, CO (1 of 2), November 12, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR058; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Elizabeth Mantey interview, Ignacio, CO (2 of 2), November 12, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR059; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Vera Sage interview, Ignacio, CO, November 13, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR060; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Liva Pacheco interview, Ignacio, CO, November 13, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR061; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Maria Valdez interview, Ignacio, CO, November 14, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR062; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Adela Quintana interview, Ignacio, CO, November 14, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR063; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Debbie Wilmer interview, Ignacio, CO, November 14, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR064; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Beverly Lyons interview, Ignacio, CO, November 15, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR065; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
      - Lillian Valencia phone interview, Ignacio, CO, December 4, 1988, AFC 2018/007: SR066; 1 audiocassette (90 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - District of Columbia
      - Marie Grosso interview, Washington, D.C., May 20, 1986, AFC 2018/007: SR067; 1 microcassette (60 min.); Recorded by Linda Pershing
    - New York